Guide to the Robert Clark papers 1940s-2005
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Robert Clark papers
1940s-2005
C0292
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
7.5 linear ft.
Articles and papers from Robert Clark's life and time working at ABC News.
Clark, Robert, 1922-2015
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Douglas and Sandra First on October 7, 2016.
Biographical Information
Robert (Bob) Clark was born in May 1922 in Omaha, Nebraska. He received a B.S. and M.A. while studying journalism and politics. He went on to become a Washington and White House correspondent for ABC News throughout the 1950s and 1970s, but continued to work for ABC until the 1990s. Most notably, he covered the assassinations of John F. Kennedy and Robert Kennedy. He was a witness to both assassinations. Later in his life, around the 1990s, he was a guest commentator on C-SPAN. Bob Clark passed away in December 2015.
Scope and Content
Series 1: JFK assassination, 1959-2005 contains articles and on-air drafts regarding the JFK assassination and the 25th anniversary of the event. There are reports of the assassination by the Review Board, autopsy reports, investigative reports, statements, and assassination theories. Included is also a binder filled with articles and reports about Kennedy's campaign and the election coverage for ABC News.
Series 2: Politics, 1950s-2004 contains articles, correspondence and on-air drafts about politicians. These include Kennedy family members, Eisenhower, Reagan, Nixon, George H.W.Bush, Billy Graham, and others.
Series 3: Foreign relations, 1965-1999 has articles and on-air drafts on topics such as Iran-Contra, relations with Cuba, Japan, Israel, Korea, India, Soviet Union, Africa and Pakistan.
Series 4: Domestic issues, 1948-1999 has articles and commentary on domestic issues such as women's rights, Medicare, religion, homosexuality, and social security.
Series 5: Personal files: 1940s-1989 has some papers written by Clark while he was a student in the 1940s as well as other materials from his life, a duplicate manuscript, and his personal correspondence.
Series 6: ABC files, 1957-1993 contains most of the drafts Clark wrote for ABC that cover a variety of topics. This series has press messages and articles, drafts from on-air commentary for ABC from the 1960s to the 1990s, perspectives written for ABC, "Issues and Answers" for ABC, negative images of the White House from 1956, radio scripts, drafts from C-SPAN shows (1990s), and interviews.
Arrangement
Organized into six series by subject. Doug First arranged the materials before donating them to SCRC.
Series 1: JFK assassination, 1959-2005 (Boxes 1-4)
Series 2: Politics, 1950s-2004 (Boxes 5-9)
Series 3: Foreign relations, 1965-1999 (Box 9)
Series 4: Domestic issues, 1948-1999 (Box 10)
Series 5: Personal files, 1940s-1989 (Box 10)
Series 6: ABC files, 1957-1993 (Boxes 11-19)
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds many other collections on 20th century political history.
Index Terms
Persons:
Eisenhower, Dwight D., (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968; Reagan, Ronald, 1911-2004
Subjects:
Journalism--United States.; Presidents--United States.
Contents List
- Series 1: JFK assassination, 1959-2005 (Boxes 1-4)
  This series contains articles and on-air drafts regarding the JFK assassination and the 25th anniversary of the event.
  - Log of ABC News Nov.22-25, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - JFK 25th Anniversary 1 of 2, 1960-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - JFK 25th Anniversary 1 of 2, 1963-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - JFK Assassination Investigation, 1962-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - JFK Assassination, 1964-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - JFK Articles, 1959-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - JFK Assassination Articles, 1961-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - JFK Assassination Review Board 1 of 3, 1978-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - JFK Assassination Review Board 2 of 3, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - JFK Assassination Review Board 3 of 3, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - JFK Assassination, Cuba 1 of 2, 1963-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - JFK Assassination, Cuba 2 of 2, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - JFK Investigation of Assassination, Exhibits V.1- V.3 1 of 2, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - JFK Investigation of Assassination, Supplemental Report 2 of 2, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - JFK Miscellaneous, 1988-2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - JFK Assassination, Theories, Articles and Reports, 1978-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - JFK Assassination, Review Board to Bob Clark, 1964-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Assassination Records Review Board 1 of 3, 1962-2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Assassination Records Review Board 2 of 3, 1957-2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Assassination Records Review Board 3 of 3, 1962-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - RFK Election Night 1964, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Press Tags, Kennedy Campaign, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Politics, 1950s-2004 (Boxes 5-9)
  This series contains articles, correspondence and on-air drafts about politicians. These include Kennedy family members, Eisenhower, Reagan, Nixon, George H.W.Bush, Billy Graham, and others.
  - Ted and Robert F. Kennedy, 1968-2004 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Robert Kennedy, 1965-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ted Kennedy, 1962-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Kennedy, Chappaquiddick, 1969-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Articles - Joe Kennedy, Bobby Kennedy, 1969-1970s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower "Fact Sheet", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Eisenhower File for TV Special, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Eisenhower 1 of 2, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Eisenhower 2 of 2, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Eisenhower, Articles, 1968-1970, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower and Illness, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Life and Funeral of Eisenhower, 1969-1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Profiles of Presidential Candidates and Results, Articles, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Assassination Attempts on Presidents, 1975-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bush, Iran (Called 5-1-85), 1977-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bush, White House Campaign, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - H.W. Bush Administration 1 of 3, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - H.W. Bush Administration 2 of 3, 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - H.W. Bush Administration 3 of 3, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nixon, Articles and Documents, 1971-1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reagan, 1984-1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hank Duel, circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - William Buckley, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Memoirs of an American Communist Lawyer, circa 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Ford Library, Conversations with Billy Graham, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Billy Graham - Correspondence and Names, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Billy Graham - Correspondence, 1977-1980, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Billy Graham, 1975-1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Billy Graham 1 of 2, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Billy Graham 2 of 2, 1979-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Wendell Willkie, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court, 1987-1999, 1979, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Supreme Court Confirmation, 1986-1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Politics - Past Years, 1988-1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Politics - 2000, Articles, 1996,1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Series 3: Foreign relations, 1965-1999 (Box 9)
  This series has articles and on-air drafts on topics such as Iran-Contra, relations with Cuba, Japan, Israel, Korea, India, Soviet Union, Africa and Pakistan.
  - Pakistan, 1965-1969, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Terrorism - Foreign and Domestic, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - White House - Articles, 1994, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Africa, Articles, 1976-1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Israeli Lobby (Called 5-2-85), 1970s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - India, Articles, 1991, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Korea, Articles, 1975-1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Japan, 1970s-1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Soviet, 1987-1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Iran Contra, Reports and Roundups, 1986-1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Israel - News Articles and Reports, 1981-1999 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Background Briefing on Cuban Situation, October 22, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Castro Memorandum, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - USS Indianapolis Testimonies, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Series 4: Domestic issues, 1948-1999 (Box 10)
  This series has articles and commentary on domestic issues such as women's rights, Medicare, religion, homosexuality, and social security.
  - Annotated Article About World War II, Unknown (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Women's Rights - Commentary ABC, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Social Security, 1987-1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Homosexuals (Including Military), 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Religion 1 of 2, 1980-1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Religion 2 of 2, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Medicare, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Broadcasting and Press, 1987-1998 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1948, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "The VIP's" manuscript and article, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Not Called", 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Series 5: Personal files, 1940s-1989 (Box 10)
  This series has some papers written by Clark while he was a student in the 1940s as well as other materials from his life, a duplicate manuscript, and his personal correspondence.
  - School Assignments, 1940s, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Duplicate Manuscript, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Series 6: ABC files, 1957-1993 (Boxes 11-19)
  This series contains most of the drafts Clark wrote for ABC that cover a variety of topics.
  - Press Message and Articles, circa 1957 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Press Message and Articles 1 of 4, circa 1956, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Press Message and Articles 2 of 4, circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Press Message and Articles 3 of 4, circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Press Message and Articles 4 of 4, circa 1957 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1963-1966, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1990,1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC: Berlin, Saigon, Seoul, 1967, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1988,1990,1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 4, 1961-1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 4, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 3 of 4, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 4 of 4, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1974-1976, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1968, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 3, 1987, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 3, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 3 of 3, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 1 of 2, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC 2 of 2, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1987-1989, 1993-1995 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, July-December 1981 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Drafts On-Air Commentary ABC, February-June 1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Perspectives, 1976-1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Perspectives, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Perspectives, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Perspectives 1 of 3, 1988-1993 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Perspectives 2 of 3, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Perspectives 3 of 3, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Issues and Answers, 1976-1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Issues and Answers, November 1960-April 1975 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Issues and Answers 1 of 6, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Issues and Answers 2 of 6, 1974-1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Issues and Answers 3 of 6, 1978-1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Issues and Answers 4 of 6, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Issues and Answers 5 of 6, 1976, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Issues and Answers 6 of 6, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Issues and Answers, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Issues and Answers, 1974, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Negatives from White House, January 26, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Radio Spots - Copies, April 25 - July 25, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - C-SPAN Shows, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Radio Scripts 1 of 3, 1991, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Radio Scripts 2 of 3, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Radio Scripts 3 of 3, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ABC Scripts (Perspectives, etc.), 1972-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Radio Spots; Women's Rights Spot, November 30, 1988-March 30, 1989; 1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Scripts, 1983-1985 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Clark Spots, July 27-December 5, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - ABC Spots, November 8, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Spots, July 28-November 29, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Original Radio Spots, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Commentaries, 1978-1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - News one Scripts, 1987-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Spots, January 14-March 11, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Spots, May 10-July 26, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Spots, April 25-July 25, 1989; July 27-December 5, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - ABC Interviews; Issues and Answers, 1975-1982 (Box 19, Folder 6)